### **DANIEL MOYA**

# **Fullstack Software Engineer**

danielmoya.dev@gmail.com https://moyadaniel.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Full stack software engineer with 6 years of **experience** in the financial, mobility, e-learning, and SaaS industry, employing **agile environments** to collectively build, improve, and maintain stable web applications turning legacy applications into modern architectures, while keeping code quality. I'm proficient in **web and mobile development**, Using for the React, Astro and Nextjs for the **front-end** and React native. And using NodeJs and Golang in the **backend** (Javascript, Php, Go, Docker).

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **CURIOUS INC**

## Hengelo, Netherlands September 2020-Present

### PROJECT: ONDERWEG APP - Mobile Engineer

- Led multi-disciplinary team to design, develop, and launch online e-learning app; prioritized and resolved 45 new features and bug fixes
- Promoted within 12 months due to strong performance and organizational impact (one year ahead of schedule)
- Created more than 80% of features for the web application.
- Expanded the app with a new module for e-learning with books, video lessons, quizzes, and exams for theory book providers, hence earning 3% revenue per item sold
- Tech Stack: Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Gradle, Java, Ruby, Android, XCode, CircleCI, Fastlane

### PROJECT: DATION DASHBOARD- Fullstack Software Engineer

- Designed migration strategy to cloud and microservices architecture after the company acquired 2 competitors and saved 66% in costs due to duplicate resources
- Improved invoices search speed by x5, helping the company maintain the revenue from a big customer
- Designed and built a recommendation algorithm for lesson appointment scheduling which increases driving school revenue by 20% and customer loyalty by 10%
- Designed and developed a supercharged agenda for driving schools management adding 10+ new features lacking in the old agenda
- Increased by 30% market positioning by refactoring 70% outdated UI pages, and features which led to a modern version of the software
- Tech Stack: HTML, Javascript, Typescript, Jquery, React, Webpack, Jest, Firebase, Unix/Linux, Golang, Apache, Php, Symfony, Doctrine, SQL, MariaDB, Postgresql, Php unit, Codeception, Selenium, CircleCI, Docker, GCP, Kubernetes, Prometheus, Grafana.

### PROJECT: SBVO PORTAL - Fullstack Software Engineer

- Built from scratch more than 80% of the main ui features of the web application
- Increased the delivery sprint by 35%
- Reduced bugs per release by 30%, took initiative in adding e2e tests for better quality assurance, testing all core
  features of the application
- Helped get 160K EUR with 4 more project phase contracts, after showcasing the main features, tested and within expected timeline in the first phase
- Tech Stack: HTML, Javascript, CSS, React, Webpack, Jest, Cypress, Firebase, Unix/Linux, PHP, Laravel, SQL, MariaDB, Postgresql, CircleCI, Docker, GCP

**H.A SYSTEMS** Caracas, Venezuela April 2020 - August 2020

### Data Engineer

• Implemented code integration, automated testing, staging, versioning and deploying helping improve the team productivity by 30% and complete goals faster

- Developed ETL pipelines to migrate DB2 database to cloud and improved by 90% the query performance and system reliability
- Engaged with high-volume data systems, facilitating seamless interaction and proficiently conducted big data analysis to extract actionable insights
- Tech Stack: UML, Go, Github Actions, SQL, Spark, DB2, AWS, RDS, CloudWatch

**EMURGO** Tokyo, Japan August 2019- March 2020

# **Software Engineer**

- Decreased by 50% the time to load (TTL) for the content and assets on the website using optimization techniques
- Boosted the traffic within a 3 months expected timeline.
- Improved the overall SEO Score for the website to 97% reaching better web search positioning.
- Created an e-commerce to strengthen commercial alliances and contribute to the company's brand positioning and revenue increase by 15% selling merchandise products
- Tech Stack: HTML, Javascript, CSS, Vue, React, MobX, NodeJs, Graphql, Webpack, Github Actions, Shopify, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Chrome Lighthouse

**BICENTENARIO BANK** Caracas, Venezuela **Software Engineer April 2019 - July 2019** 

- Reduced by 3 weeks the time to completion of the project quantifying and estimating the total efforts and planning the roadmap for the execution of the credit batch processing project
- Reduce technical debt within the organization by 25% documenting the system architecture for the credit batch processing project
- Saved by 70% development and production infrastructure costs by estimating and reserving in advanced storage space and processing capacity required for query execution given a data set
- Tech Stack: UML, RPG Language, SQL, DB2, IBM I Series

#### **EDUCATION**

**MARGARITA UNIVERSITY** 

**Bachelor of Systems Engineering**;

Nueva Esparta, Venezuela 2015-2019

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Soft Skills: Excellent technical and non-technical communication skills, detailed oriented individual, Proficient doing research, writing papers and documenting the process and the results, Ability to work independently and manage my own schedule, remarkable teammate and contributor
- Languages: English (fluent), German (basic), Spanish (native)